

jacob.kim.johnson@gmail.com

wordstosong.me

in/jacobkimjohnson

PHONE

(608)790-7675

LOCATION

Los Angeles, CA

I'm a UX/UI designer, graphic designer, and programmer with experience in industries including start-ups, nonprofits, and tech(SaaS), which has given me the distinct ability to examine situations and consider strategies from different perspectives. I have a deep passion for crafting elegant and engaging interfaces, and my creativity, empathy, critical thinking, and collaborative nature have been beneficial in helping me understand user behaviors and motivations, as well as make thoughtful decisions. Those insights have allowed me be more open-minded as I figure out the details, while focusing on the big picture.

JACOB KIM JOHNSON

EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Designer, **Graphic Designer**, and Web Developer Self-employed Aug. 2017 - Present

- Crafted user experiences by designing and developing user-centric, mobile-first web apps from scratch (using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript)
- Created UX deliverables including wireframes, prototypes, and user flows.
- Consulted with organizations on how to improve overall user experience
- Refined typography execution with font pairings, hierarchy, and spacing
- Refined aspects of visual design, like color theory and visual hierarchy/spacing
- Designed and created graphics for logos and web content
- Researched ongoing design trends, both in UX/UI and visual composition

UX/UI Designer, **Graphic Designer, and** Web Content Coordinator **CBE** International

Jul. 2014 - Sep. 2017

- Helped plan, research, test, and implement website functionality and design to improve user experience for conversion-oriented interface
- Created wireframes and mockups of web pages for updates and redesigns
- Created UX user personas and conceptualized journey maps
- Designed logo concepts for the organization's main brand and blog
- Created graphic images for internal (e.g. web headers) and external (e.g. advertisements) purposes
- Designed and edited printed marketing materials and book covers/layouts
- Coordinated with all departments and developers to ensure brand and visual consistency
- Edited and managed web content with Drupal CMS and HTML/CSS
- Improved social media strategies to be more visual, better suit reader interest, and increase interaction

Marketing Specialist (Contractor)

CATS Software, Inc. Apr. 2014 - Jul. 2014

- Researched user experience and competitors to create strategies to improve
- Experienced Agile methodology with daily meetings and JIRA for project management
- Created icons, graphics, and cartoons as companions to blog articles and social media posts
- Wrote blog posts and managed social media accounts and helped facilitate conversation for start-up organization

Marketing Intern High Noon Saloon Jun. 2010 - Jun. 2011

- Edited website design to improve clarity of information
- Created graphics for upcoming events to manage and share via social media
- Wrote and edited content for the website, regarding upcoming events

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts Luther College **Graduated May 2010**

- Major: Business Management
- Minor: Psychology **Emphasis: Marketing**

Certificate

Minneapolis Community and Technical College Completed Dec. 2014

- Graphic Design
- Web Design

SKILLED WITH

Photoshop Illustrator InDesign Sketch Invision Axure

Figma